bordgaisenergy.ie 2017-12-14

# Bord Gáis Energy - Terms, Privacy & Cookies

Please ensure that you (referred to as the "User", "you" or "your") read these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE with care as they govern your use of and access to this Web Site (the "Site"). If you do not accept them, please cease use of the Site immediately. TO USERS OF THIS SITE the following provisions apply:

  * **Introduction**

The Site is owned and operated by Bord Gáis Energy Limited (referred to as "Bord Gáis Energy Limited" "we", "us" or "our"), which expression shall also include associated companies including, where the context requires, our third party suppliers and any other person involved with the provision or maintenance of the Site. Users must use the Site and the facilities made available on it only for their intended purposes, and must at all times act in good faith when doing so.

  * **Copyright & Limited Licence**
    * All content and materials published on the Site are presented solely for your private, personal and non-commercial use. The contents of the Site, including all text, images, brands and trademarks is, unless otherwise specified, protected by national and international intellectual property laws, and is owned by Bord Gáis Energy Limited or its suppliers. Use of the Site does not give a user any ownership in or to any of that content. You are granted a non-exclusive non-transferable limited personal licence to view and download on any single computer one copy of the contents of the Site for your personal, non-commercial, home use. All copyright notices, proprietary notices and disclaimers should also be copied. You may not modify, copy, reproduce, republish, upload, post, transmit or distribute, by any means or in any manner, any material or information on or downloaded from the Site including but not limited to text, graphics, video, messages, code and/or software without our prior written consent, except where expressly invited to do so. You acknowledge that you do not acquire any ownership rights by downloading copyright material. All rights not expressly granted by us in these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE are hereby reserved. If you breach any of these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE, your authorisation to use this Site automatically terminates and you must immediately destroy any downloaded or printed materials.
    * You also understand that Bord Gáis Energy Limited cannot and does not guarantee or warrant that any material available for downloading from the Site will be free from infection, viruses and/or other code that has contaminating or destructive properties. You are responsible for implementing sufficient procedures and virus checks (inducing anti-virus and other security checks) to satisfy your particular requirements for the accuracy of data input and output.
  * **Information**
    * In accessing the Site, the User accepts that information messages and electronic mail passing over the Internet may not be free from interference by third parties. Consequently, Bord Gáis Energy Limited cannot guarantee the privacy or confidentiality of any information relating to the User passing over the Internet.
    * Users shall be responsible for the content of all communications to the Site, including its lawfulness, truthfulness and accuracy. Users must ensure that all such communications to the Site, whether by e-mail or otherwise, are free of all viruses, trojan horses, logic bombs, time bombs, worms or any other computer programmes which could prejudice the normal and proper functioning of the Site or which would do anything which if done by the user would be a breach of these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE.
  * **Online Materials**
    * Where content published on the Site is supplied by third parties, you understand that Bord Gáis Energy Limited does not control or endorse such content in any way. All content which is offered by third parties that are not affiliated with or otherwise connected with us, is published in good faith but we do not accept responsibility for the accuracy or otherwise of such contents (whether published on or offline) and the use of such content. You assume total responsibility and risk for your use of the Site and use of all information contained within it.
    * Those who visit the Site from locations outside of the Republic of Ireland do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with all applicable laws. If use of the Site and/or viewing of it, or use of any material or content on the Site or services are contrary to or infringe any applicable law in your jurisdiction(s), you are not authorised to view or use the Site and you must exit immediately.
  * **Availability of the Site**

Bord Gáis Energy Limited will try to make the Site available but cannot guarantee that the Site will operate continuously or without interruptions or be error free and can accept no liability for its unavailability. You must not attempt to interfere with the proper working of the Site and, in particular, you must not attempt to circumvent security, tamper with, hack into, or otherwise disrupt any computer system, service, web site, router or any other internet connected device.

  * **General**
    * Bord Gáis Energy Limited may alter these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE from time to time and post the new version on the Site, following which all use of the Site will be governed by that version. You must check the terms and conditions on the Site regularly.
    * These TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE are governed by Irish law.The courts of Ireland shall have exclusive jurisdiction to hear and determine all disputes, questions and differences arising out of or in connection with these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE, and the parties irrevocably submit to that jurisdiction for that purpose.
    * If any provision or term of these TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE shall become or be declared illegal, invalid or unenforceable for any reason whatsoever, such term or provision shall be severable from the other terms and conditions and shall be deemed to be deleted from them.
    * Please see our Privacy Policy and Disclaimer below:

      * Privacy Policy
      * Disclaimer
    * These TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE, our Privacy Policy and Disclaimer constitute the entire agreement between you and Bord Gáis Energy Limited and supersedes all prior written and oral arrangements, understandings, representations, warranties and agreements between Bord Gáis Energy Limited and you.

These terms and conditions are applicable in conjunction with Bord Gáis Energy's Terms and Conditions of Natural Gas & Electricity Supply, Terms and Conditions of our Website, our Website Privacy Policy and our Website Disclaimer. Please make yourself familiar with each of these sets of terms and conditions. If you do not accept any of these terms and conditions please do not proceed to set-up a Bord Gáis Energy Online Account.

##### 1.Getting Access to Your Bord Gáis Energy Online Account

To register your account online you must complete the online registration form. The fields required on this form are account number, name as it appears on your bill, email address and your telephone number. You will then be sent an email with a username and password so that you can log on to Bord Gáis Energy's online service and access your account details. Please note that when you use your username and password you are authorising us to carry out all the instructions you have given us on this site.

##### 2.Security

We will only allow you to log on and use the online account section of the site using your username and password. You must make sure that nobody else knows your username and password, even one of our customer service advisors. Please do not write them down. If you think that somebody may know your username and password, you can change your password immediately through the website or by phoning us on the number below.

##### 3.Limitation of Liability

To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, neither the Company nor any of its employees, affiliates or other representatives will be liable for loss or damages arising out of or in connection with your use of, or your inability to use, the facilities or services offered through this website, including, but not limited to, indirect or consequential loss or damages, loss of data, income, profit or opportunity, loss of or damage to property and claims of third parties, even if the Company has been advised of the possibility of such loss or damages, or such loss or damages were reasonably foreseeable.

##### 4.Provision of an Up-to-Date Email Address

For your online account to operate you must provide us with a valid and up-to-date e-mail address. Let us know immediately if you change your e-mail address in the "Edit User Details" section. Please note if you edit your email address through your online account your username will also change.

##### 5.Contacting us about your Online Account

When your account is set up and you are logged in, you can contact us by e-mail by choosing the "Contact us" link, which you can access from most pages of the site. If you would prefer you can also email the web support team directly at [helpme@bordGáis.ie](mailto:helpme@bordG%C3%A1is.ie).

##### 6.If Your Account is Unused, has Lapsed or is Duplicated

We have the right to discontinue or delete your accounts where you have:

  * Set up more than one online account (duplicate accounts) for the same supply;
  * Not used your accounts for longer than one years (unused or lapsed accounts); or
  * An account has been set up with an invalid e-mail address.

Where possible, we will attempt to contact you by email when we discontinue any accounts. Your gas supply will not be affected and we will continue to send your bills through the post. If we close or delete your online account, you can ask us for a new online account at any time.

##### 7.Closing Your Gas or Electricity Account or Changing the Gas or Electricity Supply Address for your Online Account

If you wish to close your gas or electricity account or change your Gas or Electricity Supply Address for your account if you are moving house, you must contact us with a final meter reading and if at all possible, the name of the incoming customer.

For further information please see the General Terms & Conditions of our website, our disclaimer and privacy policy, our data protection notice for Domestic Customers and our data protection notice for SME Customers.

Bord Gáis Energy Limited has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our websites.

##### Information in general:

Bord Gáis Energy's privacy & cookie policy applies to anyone who visits our websites. It explains how we may collect data from you when you visit one of our websites and how we use that information. Please take the time to carefully read this privacy & cookie policy before using our websites.

At Bord Gáis Energy we want our online services to be useful, reliable and easy to use. When you visit our websites we may use cookies to help us deliver useful functionality, improve our websites and provide relevant advertising.

##### What are cookies and how do we use them?

A cookie is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored in your web browser while you are browsing a website. There are four different types of cookies used on our websites.

##### Strictly necessary cookies

Strictly necessary cookies are essential in order to enable you to navigate around our websites and use its features. Without these cookies, we would be unable to provide certain features. 

Here are some examples of how we use these cookies:

  * Enable you to login to your online account to view your online bill.
  * To pay your bill securely online.

##### Functionality cookies

Functionality cookies allow our websites to remember choices you have made and help to provide an enhanced, more personal experience on our websites.

Here are some examples of how we use these cookies:

  * Facilitate login to our websites via Facebook Connect.
  * Allow a visitor to watch a video.
  * Enable a visitor to add comments to a forum.
  * Allow a visitor to share content on our websites on social networks.

##### Performance cookies

We use performance cookies to help us improve our websites and online services. These cookies gather information about how our sites are used, including which pages visitors go to most often. These cookies are anonymous - they don't collect information that identifies a visitor.

They also allow us to test new pages and evaluate their effectiveness, making sure we deliver the most relevant information to you and helping us to improve your experience on our websites.

Here are some examples of how we use these cookies:

  * Set video streaming speeds that are compatible with your browser.
  * Provide statistics on website usage.
  * Help us improve the website by identifying patterns and errors.

##### Advertising cookies

Advertising cookies are used to help us compile web statistics on an advertising campaign. They can also be used to deliver more relevant advertisements. These cookies are anonymous - they don't collect information that identifies a visitor.

Here are some examples of how we use these cookies:

  * Help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign.
  * Limit the number of times you see an advertisement.

A guide to behavioural advertising and online privacy has been compiled by the internet advertising industry and can be found at [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

##### How to manage your cookies:

If you no longer wish to receive cookies, you can always disable cookies through your browser settings; the Help function within your browser should tell you how. 

You can set your browser to notify you when cookies are active, or you may choose not to accept cookies at all. In additional, you can delete cookies that have already been set.

Bord Gáis Energy will assume that you agree to the placement of cookies on your device unless you specifically choose not to receive our cookies, in which case we cannot guarantee that your experience will be as fulfilling as it would otherwise be.

Bord Gáis Energy uses Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use our websites. The cookies used by this product collect information in an anonymous form. If you wish to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

##### Information relating to you:

If you fill out a form on our websites requesting information from or providing feedback to Bord Gáis Energy, we ask that you provide, amongst other things, your name, an email address and your postal address. The type of information Bord Gáis Energy collects is clearly set out on the applicable online form on our websites. We require these details to better understand the needs of visitors to our websites. This enables us to provide you with information promptly regarding the products and services which you may request from Bord Gáis Energy from time to time.

The following applies to any information you provide to Bord Gáis Energy: 

  * You authorise Bord Gáis Energy to use, store, process and disclose such information to the extent necessary to provide you with information regarding Bord Gáis Energy products and services. 
  * You will ensure that the information you provide is accurate and complete.
  * Unless specifically informed otherwise in connection with the products and services provided by Bord Gáis Energy, we will not release any of the information you provide to third parties.

##### Disclosure:

We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law. Generally we will only use your information within Bord Gáis Energy. However, sometimes we use third parties to process your information on our behalf. Bord Gáis Energy requires these third parties to comply with its instructions and we require that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way.

##### Right of access:

You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal data. Bord Gáis Energy is entitled to charge a nominal administration fee for this. If you wish to avail of this right, you should submit a written request to: 

Bord Gáis Energy - Data Protection Officer, P.O. Box 10943, Dublin 2.

In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification. If any of your details are incorrect please let us know and we will amend them.

##### Right of rectification or erasure:

If you would like any of your personal information corrected, if inaccurate, or removed from our files, you can request this to be carried out by emailing us at: [info@bordGáis.ie.](mailto:info@bordG%C3%A1is.ie) Please note, however, that if we delete your personal information it may not be possible for us to fully enable you to access all information regarding our products or services which you may request.

##### Links:

Where applicable, our websites may provide links to other websites. Privacy policies on these websites may differ from that on this website, and we advise that you review the other website's policies before providing personal information. While every care has been taken to ensure the high quality and standard of websites to which we link, Bord Gáis Energy takes no responsibility for the content of those websites and is not responsible for their data protection policies.

##### Security:

Bord Gáis Energy has taken all commercially reasonable steps to ensure the security of your communications with our websites. Information held by our websites is stored on password-protected machines, behind a firewall and not accessible to the general public via the internet. However, the confidentiality and privacy of data passing over the internet or by email cannot be guaranteed.

##### Revisions to privacy policy

Bord Gáis Energy may revise this privacy policy from time to time. Changes to this privacy policy will be posted here so you should periodically check this page to review the most recent policy.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this website, or your dealings with this website, you can contact: Bord Gáis Energy - Data Protection Officer, P.O. Box 10943, Dublin 1

##### Data Protection Notice for Residential Gas Customers

  * In order that Bord Gáis Energy may provide you with an effective service, it is necessary for Bord Gáis Energy to collect and use data relating to you while you are being supplied with natural gas. This data is used mainly to manage your customer account and for operational reasons, including, for example, visits to your premises, works required at your premises and construction and maintenance activities. In addition, data relating to you may be used for health and safety, administration, risk assessment, marketing and credit checking purposes. We may use the data relating to you to carry out credit checks and for fraud prevention with licensed agencies, fraud prevention agencies and other licensed Natural Gas Suppliers. This data may be recorded by these organisations to prevent fraud, help make credit decisions about you and for debt collection purposes. Bord Gáis Energy may keep your data for a reasonable period after you cease to be supplied with natural gas but will not keep it for any longer than is necessary and/or as required by law.
  * Bord Gáis Energy may disclose your data to other members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and agents who act on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy in connection with the activities referred to above. Such agents are only permitted to use your data as instructed by Bord Gáis Energy. They are also required to keep your data safe and secure. We may also share your data with the Sustainable Energy Authority of Ireland in order to fulfill legislative requirements.
  * From time to time you may speak to employees of Bord Gáis Energy (or agents acting on its behalf) by telephone. To ensure that Bord Gáis Energy provides a quality service, your telephone conversations may be recorded. Bord Gáis Energy will treat the recorded information as confidential and will only use it for staff training/quality control purposes, confirming details of your conversations with Bord Gáis Energy or any other purposes mentioned in this Notice.
  * If you sign-up for any of our online services and we communicate with you by email, you are responsible for the security and integrity of your own email account. You accept that electronic mail passing over the Internet may not be free from interference by third parties. Consequently, while we will take all reasonable security measures, Bord Gáis Energy cannot guarantee the privacy or confidentiality of information relating to you when passing over the Internet.
  * You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal data (Bord Gáis Energy is entitled to charge a nominal administration fee for this). If you wish to avail of this right, you should submit a written request to: Bord Gáis – Data Protection Officer, P.O. Box 51, Warrington Place, Dublin 2. In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification. If any of your details are Incorrect please let us know and we will amend them.

##### Marketing

Bord Gáis Energy, members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and/or agents acting on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy may wish to contact you by text message, e-mail, post, telephone or in person with information about products or services (relating to gas, electricity or other products and services, including those offered by third parties) which may be of interest to you.

Please follow carefully the instructions below to ensure that your marketing preferences are respected.

  * If you do not wish to be contacted by e-mail or text message with information about Bord Gáis Energy products and services which relate to the supply of natural gas, electricity or Home Team products, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.
  * If you do not wish to be contacted by post, telephone or in person with information about Bord Gáis Energy products or services, including those which may not relate to the supply of natural gas, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.

##### Data Protection Notice for Residential Electricity Customers

  * In order that Bord Gáis Energy may provide you with an effective service, it is necessary for Bord Gáis Energy to collect and use data relating to you while you are being supplied with electricity. This data is used mainly to manage your customer account and for operational reasons, including for example, visits to your Premises, works required at your Premises and construction and maintenance activities. In addition, data relating to you may be used for health and safety, administration, risk assessment, marketing and credit checking purposes. We may use the data relating to you to carry out credit checks and for fraud prevention with licensed agencies, fraud prevention agencies and other licensed electricity Suppliers. This data may be recorded by these organizations to prevent fraud, help make credit decisions about you and for debt collection purposes. Bord Gáis Energy may keep your data for a reasonable period after you cease to be supplied with electricity but will not keep it for any longer than is necessary and/or as required by law.
  * Bord Gáis Energy may disclose your data to other members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and agents who act on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy in connection with the activities referred to above. Such agents are only permitted to use your data as instructed by Bord Gáis Energy. They are also required to keep your data safe and secure. In the unlikely event of our being unable to provide you with electricity, an alternative supplier may be directed to do so by the Commission. In these circumstances, we may need to pass certain data on to the new supplier to enable it to supply you with electricity. We may also share your data with the Sustainable Energy Authority of Ireland in order to fulfil legislative requirements.
  * From time to time you may speak to employees of Bord Gáis Energy (or agents acting on its behalf) by telephone. To ensure that Bord Gáis Energy provides a quality service, your telephone conversations may be recorded. Bord Gáis Energy will treat the recorded information as confidential and will only use it for staff training/ quality control purposes, confirming details of your conversations with Bord Gáis Energy or any other purposes mentioned in this Notice.
  * If you sign-up for any of our online services and we communicate with you by email, you are responsible for the security and integrity of your own email account. You accept that electronic mail passing over the Internet may not be free from interference by third parties. Consequently, while we will take all reasonable security measures, Bord Gáis Energy cannot guarantee the privacy or confidentiality of information relating to you when passing over the Internet.
  * You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal data (Bord Gáis Energy is entitled to charge a nominal administration fee for this). If you wish to avail of this right, you should submit a written request to: Bord Gáis Energy – Data Protection, Officer, P.O. Box 51, One Warrington Place, Dublin 2. In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification. If any of your details are incorrect please let us know and we will amend them.

##### Marketing

Bord Gáis Energy, members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and/or agents acting on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy may wish to contact you by text message, e-mail, post, telephone or in person with information about products or services (relating to gas, electricity or other products and services, including those offered by third parties) which may be of interest to you.

Please follow carefully the instructions below to ensure that your marketing preferences are respected. 

  * If you do not wish to be contacted by e-mail or text message with information about Bord Gáis Energy products and services which relate to the supply of electricity, gas or Home Team products, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.
  * If you do not wish to be contacted by post, telephone or in person with information about Bord Gáis Energy products or services, including those which may not relate to the supply of electricity or gas, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.

##### Data Protection Notice for Business Gas Customers

##### Data Protection Notice for Individuals / Sole Traders

  * In order that Bord Gáis Energy may provide you with an effective service, it is necessary for Bord Gáis Energy to collect and use data relating to you while you are being supplied with Natural Gas. This data is used mainly to manage your customer account and for operational reasons, including for example, visits to your Premises, works required at your Premises and construction and maintenance activities. In addition, data relating to you may be used for health and safety, administration, risk assessment, marketing and credit checking purposes. We may use the data relating to you to carry out credit checks and for fraud prevention with licensed agencies, fraud prevention agencies and other licensed gas Suppliers. This data may be recorded by these organisations to prevent fraud, help make credit decisions about you and for debt collection purposes. Bord Gáis Energy may keep your data for a reasonable period after you cease to be supplied with Natural Gas but will not keep it for any longer than is necessary and/or as required by law.
  * Bord Gáis Energy may disclose your data to other members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and agents who act on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy in connection with the activities referred to above. Such agents are only permitted to use your data as instructed by Bord Gáis Energy. They are also required to keep your data safe and secure.
  * From time to time you may speak to employees of Bord Gáis Energy (or agents acting on its behalf) by telephone. To ensure that Bord Gáis Energyprovides a quality service, your telephone conversations may be recorded. Bord Gáis Energy will treat the recorded information as confidential and will only use it for staff training/quality control purposes, confirming details of your conversations with Bord Gáis Energy or any other purposes mentioned in this Notice.
  * You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal data (Bord Gáis Energy is entitled to charge a nominal administration fee for this). If you wish to avail of this right, you should submit a written request to: Bord Gáis, Data Protection Officer, PO Box 10310, Freepost F4062, Dublin 2. In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification. If any of your details are incorrect please let us know and we will amend them.

##### Data Protection for Other Commercial Customers

  * From time to time, the Supplier, the Supplier’s agents and/or service providers may collect from the Customer, personal data relating to the employees or other officers of the Customer. Such personal data shall be used and disclosed by the Supplier, at any time in the future, solely as strictly necessary for the purposes of managing its relationship with the Customer pursuant to the Agreement, including for contact purposes and any future sales and marketing activity.  The Customer shall procure the consent of such individuals to the uses and disclosures of personal data referred to in this Condition and shall inform the individuals that they are entitled to access their data and have any incorrect details amended or erased.
  * Throughout the course of the Customer’s ongoing customer/supplier relationship with the Supplier, the Customer may from time to time speak to the Supplier's employees (or those of its agents and/or service providers) by telephone. As part of its commitment to ensuring that the highest levels of service are provided to its customers, such telephone conversations may be recorded. The Supplier agrees to keep the recorded information in the strictest confidence and to use the information solely for staff training/quality control purposes, for verifying the Customer's instructions to the Supplier and for such other uses/disclosures as are referred to in this Condition. The Customer shall procure that its employees and other officers are informed of the terms of this Condition 25.2.

##### Marketing Notice

Bord Gáis Energy, members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and/or agents acting on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy may wish to contact you by text message, e-mail, post, telephone or in person with information about products or services (relating to gas, electricity or other products and services, including those offered by third parties) which may be of interest to you.

Please follow carefully the instructions below to ensure that your marketing preferences are respected.

  * If you do not wish to be contacted by e-mail or text message with information about Bord Gáis Energy products and services which relate to the supply of natural gas or electricity, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.
  * If you do not wish to be contacted by post, telephone or in person with information about Bord Gáis Energy products or services, including those which may not relate to the supply of natural gas, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.

##### Data Protection Notice for Business Electricity Customers

##### Data Protection Notice for Individuals / Sole Traders

  * In order that Bord Gáis Energy may provide you with an effective service, it is necessary for Bord Gáis Energy to collect and use data relating to you while you are being supplied with electricity. This data is used mainly to manage your Customer account and for operational reasons, including for example, visits to your Premises, works required at your Premises and construction and maintenance activities. In addition, data relating to you may be used for health and safety, administration, risk assessment, marketing and credit checking purposes. We may use the data relating to you to carry out credit checks and for fraud prevention with licensed agencies, fraud prevention agencies and other licensed electricity Suppliers. This data may be recorded by these organisations to prevent fraud, help make credit decisions about you and for debt collection purposes. Bord Gáis Energy may keep your data for a reasonable period after you cease to be supplied with electricity but will not keep it for any longer than is necessary and/or as required by law.
  * Bord Gáis Energy may disclose your data to other members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and agents who act on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy in connection with the activities referred to above. Such agents are only permitted to use your data as instructed by Bord Gáis Energy. They are also required to keep your data safe and secure.
  * From time to time you may speak to employees of Bord Gáis Energy (or agents acting on its behalf) by telephone. To ensure that Bord Gáis Energy provides a quality service, your telephone conversations may be recorded. Bord Gáis Energy will treat the recorded information as confidential and will only use it for staff training/quality control purposes, confirming details of your conversations with Bord Gáis Energy or any other purposes mentioned in this Notice.
  * You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal data (Bord Gáis Energy is entitled to charge a nominal administration fee for this). If you wish to avail of this right, you should submit a written request to: Bord Gáis Energy- Data Protection Officer, PO Box 10310, Freepost F4062, Dublin 2. In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification. If any of your details are incorrect please let us know and we will amend them.

##### Data Protection for Other Commercial Customers

  * From time to time, the Supplier, the Supplier’s agents and/or service providers may collect from the Customer, personal data relating to the employees or other officers of the Customer. Such personal data shall be used and disclosed by the Supplier, at any time in the future, solely as strictly necessary for the purposes of managing its relationship with the Customer pursuant to the Agreement, including for contact purposes and any future sales and marketing activity.  The Customer shall procure the consent of such individuals to the uses and disclosures of personal data referred to in this Condition and shall inform the individuals that they are entitled to access their data and have any incorrect details amended or erased.
  * Throughout the course of the Customer’s ongoing customer/supplier relationship with the Supplier, the Customer may from time to time speak to the Supplier's employees (or those of its agents and/or service providers) by telephone. As part of its commitment to ensuring that the highest levels of service are provided to its customers, such telephone conversations may be recorded. The Supplier agrees to keep the recorded information in the strictest confidence and to use the information solely for staff training/quality control purposes, for verifying the Customer's instructions to the Supplier and for such other uses/disclosures as are referred to in this Condition. The Customer shall procure that its employees and other officers are informed of the terms of this Condition 21 (b).

##### Marketing Notice (applies to all Customers)

Bord Gáis Energy, members of the Bord Gáis Energy group and/or agents acting on behalf of Bord Gáis Energy may wish to contact you by text message, e-mail, post, telephone or in person with information about products or services (relating to gas, electricity or other products and services, including those offered by third parties) which may be of interest to you.

Please follow carefully the instructions below to ensure that your marketing preferences are respected.

  * If you do not wish to be contacted by e-mail or text message with information about Bord Gáis Energy products and services which relate to the supply of natural gas or electricity, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.
  * If you do not wish to be contacted by post, telephone or in person with information about Bord Gáis Energy products or services, including those which may not relate to the supply of natural gas, please exercise your right of opt-out as described in the Marketing Opt-out form section.

##### How to exercise your right of opt-out

When registering your marketing preferences with us, you are responsible for recording your preferences accurately. If you have multiple accounts with Bord Gáis Energy, you must ensure that your preferences are recorded accurately and inform us which accounts you wish to opt-out from.

You can exercise your right of opt-out by either:

  * Writing to us at:  
Bord Gáis Energy  
Data Protection Opt-Out  
PO Box 10310  
Freepost F4062  
Dublin 1

OR

  * completing the opt-out Web Form below:

**Please enable JavaScript in order to complete the opt-out Web Form**
